Pritesh Neelesh Zaveri

- ✓ Ridgevale drive, Markham, ON L6B 1A8
- priteshzaveri27@gmail.com
- +1-647-724-1079
- https://www.priteshzaveri.com/



Professional Summary

Goal-oriented Senior UI Developer with 4+ years of experience in building more than 28 responsive websites, 12 blogs, 5 data dashboards, REST APIs, HTML e-mailers, Web Components, Highly optimized landing pages, and Ad integrations for the Ad Tech industry. Committed to high standards of web development with browser support for all major browsers.



Employment History

Senior UI Developer @ Media.net Software Services (India) Pvt. Ltd Mumbai, India

Dec. 2017 - current

- Converted PSD and Zeplin designs to Web pages using HTML, CSS, and Javascript.
- Created 15 WordPress websites with custom themes built from scratch, 17 Product websites built on CakePHP framework, and 8 Product Listing and Comparison Websites in Reactls. All websites are mobile responsive up to 320px.
- Developed 5 highly optimized dashboards using ReactJs to help business teams visualize the key performance indicators and other strategic data for the organization at a glance.
- Mentored 4 new joiners to help them get on board in the team and trained them well.
- Improved existing development process by introducing OOP style of programming and helping in overall reduction of more than 40% in website development time.
- Actively took interviews and helped to bring new talent to the team.
- Expertise in creating highly optimized Search Engine Results Page with Google DFP/ADX integration along with the integrations of Taboola and Outbrain Ad Units.

Application Development Analyst @ Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd Mumbai, India

Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2017

- Created 7 independent Automation utilities usin VBA, excel macros and java that resulted in more than 3000 hrs and \$750,000 worth of savings in 1 financial year which was highly appreciated by the client.
- Won star employee of the month twice in 6 months.
- Created a dashboard for monitoring daily team activites. This helped in increasing the team productivity by more than 40%.

Freelance App Developer @ Vow Jewels LLP.

Mumbai, India

July 2020 — Nov. 2020

• Developed a mobile application with payment gateway integration based on client requirements and specifications using Ionic 4, Laravel and MySQL. The app is deployed and published on Google PlayStore since November 2020.

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=vow.gold.investment



Skills

HTML

HTML5 · Markdown

CSS

Sass · Bootstrap · PostCSS

JavaScript

React · Ionic · Angular

PHP

 $Laravel \cdot CakePHP \cdot WordPress$

Backend

NodeJs · Python

Databases

MySQL · MongoDB

UI\UX Tools

Photoshop · Figma · Zeplin



Languages

English

Hindi



Education

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T

K.J. Somaiya College of Engineering 2012-2016